# alex gilbert

4555 15<sup>th</sup> Ave NE #119• seattle, washington • 98105 **CELL** (408) 643-4577 • **E-MAIL** agilbe@uw.edu • **PORTFOLIO** agilbe.github.io

#### **PROFILE**

Creative, resourceful, and dedicated team player with an enthusiasm for technology, design, problem solving, and learning. Interested in harnessing the power of computers and their users to solve problems of all kinds.

Development proficiencies: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, REST APIs (JSON/XML)

Design proficiencies: mockups, prototypes, user + usability research, storyboards, wireframes

Design tools: Balsamiq, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science, Informatics and Human Centered Design & Engineering University of Washington

**Expected graduation date: June 2018** 

Relevant Coursework: Computer Programming I + II, Data Structures, Interactive Systems Design, Relational Databases, Technical Writing, User Research, User-Centered Design, Visual Communication, Web Programming

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, Human Centered Design & Engineering, UW SEATTLE. WA - 2016 - PRESENT

- Assisted students in learning introductory programming and design through Python as part of HCDE 310, Interactive Systems Design.
- Collaborated with teaching team to develop training tools and documentation for relevant technologies (Linux Mint, Python, git, Google Cloud SDK, and more)

## Volunteer Undergraduate Research Assistant, Behavioral Research and Therapy Clinics, UW SEATTLE, WA - 2015

Assisted in the OASIS project, conducting usability tests for an online intervention course to determine the
efficiency of computerized intervention for heavy drinkers.

### **Team Member, Marshalls**

SAN JOSE, CA - 2013 - 2015

Worked in all areas of the store, on the floor, in the backroom, and as a cashier.

### **LEADERSHIP**

### Treasurer, Human Centered Design and Engineering Student Association, UW SEATTLE, WA - 2016 – PRESENT

Maintained RSO finances, including but not limited to recording all expenditures and fundraising for events.
 Helped plan major-wide events.

### First Year Representative, Informatics Undergraduate Association, UW SEATTLE, WA - 2016 – PRESENT

 Acted as a liaison between the Informatics first year student body and the IUGA board, making first year students' voices heard and helping to plan major-wide events with first year students' interests in mind.